A Guide to the William M. Anderson, Jr. Records, 1974-2006
Simpson Library, University of Mary Washington
- Series 17: President's Correspondence, 1980-2006 (RESTRICTED MATERIAL INTERFILED -all folders in series)
  - President's Correspondence, 1995 January-June (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - President's Correspondence, 1995 July-December (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - President's Correspondence, 1996 January-June (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - President's Correspondence, 1996 July-December (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - President's Correspondence, 1997 January-July (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - President's Correspondence, 1997 August-September (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - President's Correspondence, 1997 October-December (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - President's Correspondence, 1998 January-February (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - President's Correspondence, 1998 March-April (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - President's Correspondence, 1998 May-June (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - President's Correspondence, 1998 July-August (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - President's Correspondence, 1998 September-October (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - President's Correspondence, 1998 November-December (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - President's Correspondence, 1999 January-February (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - President's Correspondence, 1999 March-April (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - President's Correspondence, 1999 May-June (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - President's Correspondence, 1999 July-August (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - President's Correspondence, 1999 September-October (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - President's Correspondence, 1999 November-December (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - President's Correspondence, 2000 January-March (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - President's Correspondence, 2000 April (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - President's Correspondence, 2000 May-June (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - President's Correspondence, 2000 July-August (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - President's Correspondence, 2000 September-October (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - President's Correspondence, 2000 November-December (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - President's Correspondence, 2001 January-February (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - President's Correspondence, 2001 March-April (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - President's Correspondence, 2001 May-June (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - President's Correspondence, 2001 July-September (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - President's Correspondence, 2001 October-December (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - President's Correspondence, 2002 January-April (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - President's Correspondence, 2002 May-August (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - President's Correspondence, 2002 September-December (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - President's Correspondence, 2003 January-June (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - President's Correspondence, 2003 July-December (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - President's Correspondence, 2004 January-June (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - President's Correspondence, 2004 July-December (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - President's Correspondence, 2005 January-May (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - President's Correspondence, 2005 July-December (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - President's Correspondence, 2006 January-June (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Faculty & Staff, 1990-1992 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1984 April-1987 March (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987 April-August (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987 September-December (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988 January-April (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988 May-August (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988 September-December (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1989 January-February (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1989 March (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1989 April-May (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991 June-August (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991 September-October (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991 November (Note: contains photographs) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991 December (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1992 January-March (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1992 April-June (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1992 July-September (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1992 October-December (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1993 January-March (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1993 April-June (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1993 July-August (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1993 September-October (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1993 November-December (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Student Letters, 1990-1992 (RESTRICTED) (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991-2006 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence to Faculty, Staff and Students, 1980-1983 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Students, Parents of, Miscellaneous Letters (RESTRICTED) (Box 28, Folder 9)
- Series 18: Committees, 1985-2006
  - President's Advisory Committee on University Mission and Governance, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - MWC Committee Membership, 1991-1992 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Honor System Implementation Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Monitoring and Advisory Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Strategic Planning Committee, 1996-2006 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Hazard Communication Committee, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Public Affairs Advisory Committee, 1985-1988 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Recruitment and Retention Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Unfair Competition Committee, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Personnel Advisory Committee (PAC), 1990 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Strategic Planning Committee, 1990-1991 (SOME RESTRICTED MATERIAL) (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Committee for In-State Residency, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 12)
- Series 19: Community Relations, 1986-1994
  - Chamber of Commerce - President, 1986-1991 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Rappahannock United Way, 1982-1989 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Chamber Retreat, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - ChamberFest, 1987-1990 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Christ Church School Board of Governors, 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax County Public Schools, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - City Council, 1989-1991 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Series 20: Faculty Affairs, 1961-1994
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1987-1990 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Meeting (85th Anniversary), 1993 August (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Secretary, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Survey Results - Faculty Response, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Leidecker, Kurt F., 1961-1994 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Series 21: Conferences and Workshops, 1989-1993
  - The Breakers Conference, 1989 July (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Trenton State College Conference, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - University of New Orleans Workshop, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Southern University Conference, 1989 (Note: contains photograph) (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Southern University Conference, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Southern University Conference, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Southern University Conference, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Southern University Conference, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 20)
- Series 22: President's Book Club, 1998-2006
  - Executive Committee Administrative Documents, 1998-2006 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Suggested Authors, 1998-2000 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Suggested Authors, 2001-2007 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Albright, Madeline, 2005 Fall (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Baldacci, David, 1999 Spring (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Beschloss, Michael, 2003 Fall (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Civil War Panel: Administrative Files, 2001 Fall (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Civil War Panel: Gannon, James, 2001 Fall (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Civil War Panel: McMath, Meredith, 2001 Fall (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Civil War Panel: Morton, Virginia, 2001 Fall (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Civil War Panel: Zimmer, Anne, 2001 Fall (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Collins, Nancy, 2004 Spring (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Craig, Philip R., 2001 Spring (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Emerson, Claudia, 2006 Spring (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Giovanni, Nikki, 2001 Spring (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Jenkins, Emyl, 2006 Fall (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Jenkins, Peter, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - McCourt, Frank, 2003 Spring (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - McCullough, David, 2002 Spring (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Morris, Willie, 1998 Fall (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Muller, Judy, 2000 Fall (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Pilcher, Rosamunde, 1999 Fall (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Robertson, James, 2000 Spring (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Roundtree, Susan, 2004 Fall (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Sally, 2005 Spring (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Wiseman, Rosalind, 2004 Fall (Box 32, Folder 17)
- Series 23: Speeches, 1984-2005
  - Miscellaneous, 1996, 1998-2000, 2003-2004 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988, 1991, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985-1987 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Ring Presentation, 1999-2005 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Ring Presentation, 1985, 1987-1988, 1990-1996, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - State of the College, 1985-1987 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - State of the College, 2002 (Note: contains 2 audio cassette tapes) (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Commencement, 1996-1998, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1987, 1988, 1988 (rain plan) (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Convocation, 1991-1992, 1996, 1998-2001 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Convocation, 1987-1989 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Remarks, 2002-2005 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Remarks, 1996, 1999-2001 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Remarks, 1994-1995 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Remarks, 1985-1986, 1988, 1992-1993 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Orientation, 1985-1988, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Orientation, 1992-1993, 1995-1996 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Honor Convocation, 1986, 1992, 1996, 1998-2000 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Inauguration Address, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - James Monroe Birthday Celebration, 1984, 1986, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 7)
- Series 24: Miscellaneous, 1977-2005
  - MWC Alumni Association, 1977-1983 (SOME RESTRICTED MATERIAL) (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Bobbie Burton, Director of Alumni Affairs, 1981-1983 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Federal Legislation Reporting, 1990-1991 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Frisbee (Golf), 1986-1988 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Historic Gordonsville, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Tribute to President Anderson, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Procurement Management Review, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Retention Reports/Studies, 1991-1992 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Richard Bland College - MWC Statement of Agreement, 1988-1990 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - ROTC Program, 1985-1993 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Snowmass Institute, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - President's Task Force, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Volunteerism, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - International Association of University Presidents, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Mrs. Leidecker's Memorial Service, 1989 April 5 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Melle, Frances, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Menokin (Historic Preservation), 1987 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Peer Institutions, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1983-1993 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - News Clippings, 1996-2006 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Anderson, William M., Jr. - Biographical Materials (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Thomas Jefferson Institute for Study of Religious Freedom, 1974-1996 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Thomas Jefferson Institute for Study of Religious Freedom, 1983-1998 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Interviews, 1987 October (Note: contains audio cassette tape) (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Presidential Search, 1983 (SOME RESTRICTED MATERIAL) (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, William M. Jr., Photographs and AEC [Alumni Executive Center] Photographs, 2005 February (Note: contains CD-ROM) (Box 38, Folder 5)